# Foo Xianyang (Frankie)

Email: frankiefoo732@hotmail.com

*Mobile no:* +60 12 520 3928

Nationality: Malaysia

Spoken Languages: English, Chinese, Malay

LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/frankiefoo/

# **Profile Summary**

I am a passionate software engineer who aims to deliver useful innovation and bring meaningful impact to end-users through the adoption of technology.

I have more than 7 years of experience of software development experience, majority of them are spent in automated test equipment industry, as well as electronics manufacturing industry. I've developed software that operates in some of the world's major electronics manufacturer's factory.

I see myself as an independent, courageous, analytical person, and as a team player with leadership qualities. I'm looking forward to environment that allows me to excels & improve in what I do, to practice continuous learning, as well as achieving a good work/life balance.

## **Education and Certification**

Highest Education: Bachelor's Degree in Science University: Universiti Sains Malaysia

Course: Computer Science, majored in distributed system & security

CGPA: 3.59 Year Obtained: May 2010

Certifications: Xamarin Certified Mobile Developer (March 2017)

Microsoft AZURE207x: Databases in Azure (January 2017) Microsoft AZURE214x: Azure Fundamentals (December 2016)

## **Technical Skills**

Advance: C#, Xamarin Forms

Intermediate: C++/CLI, Windows Forms, SQLite, Xamarin, WPF, XAML, Python,

Ruby, Rails, JavaScript

Basic: ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Web API, MS SQL Server, Azure services,

HockeyApp, Tcl/Tk, Shell script

Beginner: Perl, Powershell

# **Professional Experience**

#### A. Invantest DSG Sdn Bhd

Period: May 2017 – Present

Designation: Senior Software Development Engineer

Type: Full time (Permenant)

## Job Scope

Design & develop automation system for semiconductor manufacturers.

#### Technologies:

Python, Tcl/Tk, Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, Shell script, Postgres, C#, Powershell, CentOS/RedHat, Windows

#### **B.** Straits Software

Period: May 2016 – Present
Designation: Software Consultant
Type: Self-Employed

### Job Scope

- Provide mobile application consultation & development services
- Provide enterprise application consultation & development services
- Provide website consultation & development services
- Provide software engineering consultation services
- Provide technical training on Xamarin

#### *Projects involved (selected):*

- Mobile application for loyalty program platform
  - Provide technical consultation on how to develop the platform from ground up
  - Develop business-facing Android mobile application using Xamarin. Forms
  - Develop consumer-facing iOS mobile application using Xamarin. Forms
  - Provide post-release software management through telemetry & distribution services using HockeyApps
- Mobile application for crowdsourced grocery price tracker
  - Develop Android mobile application using Xamarin.Forms
  - Design, develop and publish web services endpoint using Azure App Service (Mobile Apps) & Asp.Net Web API
  - Design and develop SQL storage using Azure SQL database
- Cross-platform mobile app development with Xamarin.Forms
  - Provide Xamarin. Forms technical training for working professionals
  - Conducted at The Coding\_Shophouse, Penang
- MS SQL database performance analyzer and technical training
  - Ad-hoc consultation for a Japanese MNC
  - Provide technical training on using MS SQL database performance analyzer
  - Provide best-practice training on database querying

#### Technologies:

C#, Xamarin, Xamarin.Forms, HockeyApps, Azure App Services (Mobile App), Azure SQL database, Asp.Net Web API

# C. Intel Technology Sdn Bhd

*Period:* Aug 2015 – May 2016

Designation: Software Development Engineer

Type: Full-time (Contract)

## Job Scope:

Working with business team to manage, investigate & resolve L3 incident

- Collaborate with collateral system/interface's stakeholder in manage, investigate & resolve L3 incident
- Provide resolution/workaround to end-user on L3 incident
- Support & maintain existing business application
- Document application design, behavior & architecture

## Technologies:

C#, WPF, XAML, PL/SQL

## D. Aemulus Corporation Berhad

PeriodApril 2014 – Aug 2015DesignationSoftware StrategistTypeFull-time (Permanent)

#### Job Scope:

- Perform competitive analysis and provide potential R&D software roadmap
- Perform requirement gathering & analysis on potential project
- Take the lead role in determining R&D software's UX, UI & usability design
- Design, develop, test, deploy and document user-centric software for semiconductor testers and manufacturing systems
- Design, develop, test, deploy & support user-centric software to optimize & supplement existing enterprise resource planning & manufacturing business process
- Support & maintain existing internal business software
- Working with external vendor to improve & upgrade existing enterprise software solution

#### Accomplishments:

- Designed, customized and integrated production system to client's existing production work flow
- Designed & developed desktop based tools for supply chain & marketing department, to compensate for limits of existing web based ERP & MRP system
- Designed & developed web based tools for manufacturing department to record manufactured product lifecycle incident, from manufacturing till after-sales service record.
- Designed & developed desktop based tool to enable supply chain & warehouse operation to adopt faster cadence of just-in-time manufacturing process

- Designed & integrated barcode solution into warehouse & manufacturing operation for more accurate and accountable inventory management process
- Championed and lead 2 successful upgrade process to existing ERP and MRP software

#### Technologies:

C#, C++/CLI, Asp.Net MVC, Microsoft SQL Server, Windows Forms, SQLite, Mono

# E. Aemulus Corporation Berhad

Period:April 2012 – April 2014Designation:Advance R&D EngineerType:Full-time (Permanent)

#### Job Scope:

- Take the lead role in determining software's UX, UI & usability design
- Perform competitive analysis and provide potential roadmap/feature suggestion
- Perform requirement gathering & analysis on potential project
- Design, develop, test, deploy and document user-centric software for semiconductor testers and manufacturing systems
- Define software requirements and standards together with Marketing and other development disciplines
- Maintain existing software, which includes fixing software bugs in existing codes, and troubleshooting issues on test systems
- Develop and maintain technical collateral such as application notes, user guides, user manuals and training manuals
- Provide technical support and training on Aemulus software products to external & internal clients.
- Create demonstration software packages which include sales tools, development programs and interactive presentations
- Travel to client's site to perform requirement gathering and support system installation/commissioning of tester system

## Accomplishments:

- Co-designed & developed brand-new back-end infrastructure for new test-management software suite
- Designed & developed brand-new front-end program, as the central point of all user interaction of the new software suite.
- Provide design guidelines for the new test-management software suite and it's companion software, to achieve intuitive user-experience & design across board.
- Increased performance level of production control system by optimizing it's internal process and workflow.
- Modularized production control system to allow easier customization process for each client, and to reduce difference between standard and customized variants.
- Increased performance level of report generation tool by multiple fold, and enabled faster turnaround time for customer with huge production data
- Designed & developed new project test management system, which allow easy deployment of test programs from client's engineering site to her factory floor worldwide via different technology
- Designed, developed, and integrated customs application to handler machine, in order to enable testers to be sold as turn-key solutions

- Designed, customized and integrated production system to client's existing production work flow
- Designed, developed and integrated custom line-of-business application to client's existing R&D and engineering work flow
- Successful project roll out in clients' multi local and oversea factory site
- Admiral Award for excellent work contribution

#### Technologies:

C#, C++/CLI, SQLite, Windows Forms, XML

## F. Aemulus Corporation Berhad

Period: June 2010 – April 2012

Designation: R&D Engineer

Type: Full-time (Permanent)

## Job Scope:

- Design, develop, test, deploy and document user-centric software for semiconductor testers and manufacturing systems
- Define software requirements and standards together with Marketing and other development disciplines
- Maintain existing software, which includes fixing software bugs in existing codes, and troubleshooting issues on test systems
- Develop and maintain technical collateral such as application notes, user guides, user manuals and training manuals
- Provide technical support and training on Aemulus software products to external & internal clients.
- Create demonstration software packages which include sales tools, development programs and interactive presentations
- Travel to client's site to perform requirement gathering and support system installation/commissioning of tester system

## Accomplishments:

- Designed & developed companion production system for semiconductor testers sold to clients, and deployed to factory environment
- Designed & developed multi-format dynamic report templating and generation tools, to produce production lot data analysis and test flow book keeping report
- Designed, customized and integrated production system to client's existing production work flow
- Designed, developed and integrated custom line-of-business application to client's existing R&D and engineering work flow
- Designed & developed basic network project test management system
- Complied helper class/macro to enable easier application of tester's API to client's existing test program flow
- Created manuals, training materials, software packages for external & internal customers
- Performed competitive analysis on competitor product, and proposed features roadmap that were implemented in the next version
- Successful project roll out in clients' multi local and oversea factory site

## Technologies:

# C#, C++/CLI, SQLite, Windows Forms, XML, FTP

# G. Intel Microelectronics Sdn Bhd

Period: December 2008 – September 2009

Designation: Intern
Type: Internship